vitaminsAndMineralsQuestions = [
    {
        "question": "Which individuals require vitamin supplementation",
		"choices": "specific deficiencies, medical indications, conditions affecting absorption, conditions affecting vitamin need, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "General recommendations for multivitamins that is false is",
		"choices": "look for 100%, thiamine, riboflavin, niacin, B6, folic acid, B12, D, E, and C, limit vitamin C and minerals other than calcium and magnesium, include vitamin K unless there is anticoagulant use",
        "answer": "limit vitamin C and minerals other than calcium and magnesium",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "How is vitamin intake quantitated",
		"choices": "dietary reference intakes, recommended dietary allowance, daily value, tolerable upper intake level, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Select all the active forms of vitamin A",
		"choices": "retinol, retinal, beta carotene, retinoic acid",
        "answer": "retinol, retinal",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one is not a normal function of vitamin A",
        "choices": "Rhodopsin pigment in eyes, epithelial barrier function, antioxidant, cell division and transcription",
		"answer": "cell division and transcription",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where do you look for vitamin deficiency in. Select all that apply",
		"choices": "premature infants, GI conditions of fat malabsorption, developed countries with limited food intake",
        "answer": "premature infants, GI conditions of fat malabsorption",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the signs of vitamin A deficiency, dry, s___ skin, increased infectious diseases such as m____, m_____, d____ eyes, impaired a___, t___, s___",
		"answer": "scaly, measles, malaria, dry, appetite, taste, smell",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vitamin excess leads to",
		"choices": "increased lung cancer risk in smokers, bleeding, liver toxicity, joint and bone pain, risk of osteoporosis, dry skin, gingivitis, birth defects, alopecia, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Acute overdose of vitamin A leads to increased i____ pressure, h__, s___, d___",
        "answer": "intracranial, headaches, seizures, drowsiness",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "You can look for vitamin A excess in",
		"choices": "use of retinoid drugs, use of fish liver oil, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the daily requirement of vitamin A for male/female ____/____ug/day, ____IU vitamin A, ____IU beta carotene from supplements, ___ IU beta carotene from food",
        "answer": "900/700, 3000, 6000, 18000",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the UL for vitamin A ___ug/day",
		"choices": "3000",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "The three different forms of vitamin D are e___, c____, 1,25-d_____",
		"answer": "ergocalciferol, cholecalciferol, dihydroxycholecalciferol",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ergocalciferol (D2) is present in p___ and f___",
        "answer": "plants, fungi",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "cholecalciferol (D3) is synthesized in skin in presence of s___, present in f___ foods",
        "answer": "sunlight, fortified",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "What effect does vitamin D deficiency have",
		"choices": "muscle weakness, lupus, rheumatoid arthritis, rickets, osteomalacia, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Calcitriol (Rocaltrol) is a p___ product",
        "answer": "prescription",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vitamin D excess leads to ___ complaints, h____",
        "answer": "GI, hypercalcemia",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the normal function of vitamin E",
		"choices": "antioxidant protection against damage, involvement in immune function, inhibition of protein kinase C, decreases endothelial adhesion, increases vasodilation, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the daily requirement of vitamin D for male/female (1-70yo) ____ug/day ( ____IU)",
        "answer": "15, 600",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the daily requirement of vitamin D for male/female (70+ yo) ______ug/day (___IU)",
        "answer": "20, 800",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the UL for vitamin D (>=9yo) ______ug/day (____IU)",
        "answer": "100, 4000",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "You need ____ minutes of midday sun exposure from 10Am-3PM for ___ times/week ",
        "answer": "5-30, 2",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vitamin E deficiency leads to free radical damage to neuronal, muscle, and other membranes, p___ neuropathy, r____, a___, impaired immune function",
        "answer": "peripheral, retinopathy, ataxia",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vitamin E excess leads to increased bleeding at high doses, i___ mortality, decreased effect of r___ therapy",
        "answer": "increased, radiation",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "The daily requirement of vitamin E for male/female is _____mg/day (_____IU)",
        "answer": "15, 15.5-22.5",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "The UL for vitamin E in male/female is ____mg/day",
        "answer": "1000",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one is not a normal function of thiamine",
		"choices": "carbohydrate metabolism, nervous function, gain fat",
        "answer": "gain fat",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Dry beriberi affects p___ nervous system",
        "answer": "peripheral",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one is not a symptom of dry beriberi",
		"choices": "loss of tendon reflexes, paresthesia, numbness of feet, foot/wrist drop, emaciation, painful tender muscles (pain on compression), aphonia, edema",
        "answer": "edema",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one is not a symptom of wet beriberi",
		"choices": "dyspnea, otheopnea, slight cyanosis, edema, wenicke's syndrome, dilation of right heart/heart failure, emaciation",
        "answer": "emaciation",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Wet beriberi affects c____ system",
        "answer": "cardiovascular",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Wernicke's encephalopathy is the acute phase and includes c___, a___, e___ weakness/p___",
        "answer": "confusion, ataxia, eye, paralysis",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Korsakoff's syndrome is the chronic phase and includes memory loss and visual impairment and is known as a___induced persisting a___disorder and can be irreversible",
        "answer": "alcohol, amnestic",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "There is no UL for thiamine excess",
		"choices": "true, false",
        "answer": "true",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the daily requirement of thiamine for male/female __/__mg/day",
        "answer": "1.3/1.1",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the normal function of riboflavin",
		"choices": "Electron transport and ATP production, Glutathione reductase (antioxidant), metabolism of B6/niacin/folate, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Riboflavin deficiency needs to be watched in e___, a___, use of oral c____, long term a_____, t___ antidepressants",
        "answer": "elderly, alcoholics, contraceptives, antibiotics, tricyclic",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Riboflavin deficiency is also known as a___",
        "answer": "ariboflavinosis",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "riboflavin deficiency results in",
		"choices": "cheilosis, scaly skin, magenta tongue, GI irritatiion, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Daily requirement of riboflavin for male/female is ___/___mg.day",
        "answer": "1.3/1.1",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "____ mg tryptophan = 1 mg niacin",
        "answer": "60",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "riboflavin has no known UL",
		"choices": "true, false",
        "answer": "true",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one is not a normal function of niacin",
		"choices": "Electron transport and ATP production, protein and lipid synthesis and metabolism, DNA repair/cell cycling and differentiation, lipoprotein regulation, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "none of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Niacin deficiency needs to be watched in a____, diets rich in corn not a____ with lime, i___ therapy, use of bile acid binding resins",
        "answer": "alcoholics, alkalinized, isoniazid",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Niacin deficiency leads to",
		"choices": "pellagra, dermatitis, diarrhea, dementia, facial lesions, dementia, glove-and-stocking lesions, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Niacin excess leads to f___, headache, i___, GI problems, atrial a____, hepatotoxicity, h____",
        "answer": "flushing, itching, arrhythmias, hyperglycemia", 
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "The daily requirement of niacin for male/female is ____/____mg/day and the UL is ____mg/day and the therapeutic dose is ____mg/day",
        "answer": "16/14, 35, 500-3000",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pyridoxine is used for",
		"choices": "transamination, synthesis of heme, fatty acids, neurotransmitters, homocysteine metabolism, gluconeogenesis, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pyridoxine deficiency leads to",
		"choices": "peripheral neuropathy, convulsions, decreased cognition, depression, cheilosis, decreased immune function, microcytic anemia, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pyridoxine excess leads to",
		"choices": "sensory neuropathy, skin disorders, photosensitivity, GI symptoms, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "The daily requirement of pyridoxine for male/female is ___mg/day, the UL is ___mg/day",
		"answers": "1.3, 100",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "The normal function of biotin is",
		"choices": "gluconeogenesis, fatty acid, amino acid synthesis, histone binding in nucleus and protein expression, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Biotin deficiency leads to",
		"choices": "thinning hair/faceial rash/dermatitis, uncombable hair syndrome, depression, peripheral neuropathy, GI symptoms, failure to thrive, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Biotin deficiency needs to be watched in",
		"choices": "smoking, anticonvulsants, intake of raw egg, TPN without biotin, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "The daily requirement of biotin for male/female is ____ug/day, the UL is ___ug/day",
        "answer": "30, 100",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Biotin is synthesized by g___ bacteria",
        "answer": "gut",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "1 ug food folate= _DFE=_ug supplement or fortified food",
		"answer": "1,0.6",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "The funcion of folate is to",
		"choices": "cofactor for methylation reactions in nucleic acid synthesis and cell division, metabolism of amino acids, interaction with vitamins B6 and B12, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Folic acid deficiency leads to",
		"choices": "mouth soreness and ulceration, megaloblastic anemia, including weakness, irritability, difficulty concentrating, developmental defects, neural tube, low birthweight, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Folic acid excess leads to",
		"choices": "Gi, confusion, sleep disturbance, progression of preneoplastic lesions, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Folate deficiency needs to be watched in",
		"choices": "women of child bearing age, alcoholics, smokers, drugs that antagonize folic acid including methotrexate, anticonvulsants, diuretics, antibiotics, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Folic acid excess needs to be watched in supplementation e__",
        "answer": "excess",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vitamin B12 is NOT needed for",
		"choices": "metabolism of amino acids, synthesis of DNA/hemoglobin/myeline, interacts with folate and B6, involved with homocysteine metabolism",
        "answer": "metabolism of amino acids",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "The daily requirement of folic acid for male/female is ___ug/day, for pregnancy/lactation ____ug/day, and the UL is ____mg/day",
        "answer": "400, 6000/500, 1",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vitamin B12 deficiency leads to",
		"choices": "ataxia, confusion, depression, dementia, peripheral neuropathy, mouth soreness, pernicious anemia, impaired fetal and infant growth, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "B12 deficiency needs to be watched in",
		"choices": "unsupplemented vegan diet, loss of intrinsic factor (pernicious anemia, gastric atrophy, GI disorders, use of PPI/H2A/metformin, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "There is no B12 UL",
		"choices": "true, false",
        "answer": "true",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "The daily requirement of vitamin B12 for male/female is ____ug/day, and there is ___UL",
        "answer": "2.4, no",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "The normal function of vitamin C is",
		"choices": "antioxidant activity, needed for synthetic and metabolic functions, needed for immune function, facilitates iron absorption, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vitamin C deficiency leads to",
		"choices": "bruising, bleeding in gums, fatigue/depression/irritability, slow wound healing, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vitamin C excess leads to",
		"choices": "potential dental erosion from lozenges/chewable tablets, GI symptoms, increased oxalate and kidney stone, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vitamin C is destroyed by cooking and storage",
		"choices": "true, false",
        "answer": "true",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "The daily requirement of Vitamin C for male/female is ___/___mg/day, the UL is ___mg/day, and _____mg/day if prone to kidney stones",
        "answer": "90/75, 2000, 1000",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "General concerns regarding minerals is factors increasing absorption such as i___stomach acid, mineral d___, g____abnormalities",
        "answer": "increased, deficiency, genetic",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "General concerns regardig minerals is factors decreasing absorption such as d___stomach acid, i____damage, s___ of transport proteins",
        "answer": "decreased, intestinal, saturation",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "general issues regarding minerals is non absorption such as s___ texture, GI u___, d___drug absorption",
        "answer": "stool, upset, decreased",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Calcium deficiency leads to",
		"choices": "osteopenia, skeletal abnormalities, numbness and tingling, cardiac arrhythmias, muscle cramps/tetany, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Calcium excess leads to",
		"choices": "calcium precipitation in heart or kidney, constipation, increased cardiovascular risk, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "The daily requirement of calcium is ___mg/day for 9-19 yo",
        "answer": "1300",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "The daily requirement of calcium for male/female is ___mg/day for 19-50 yo",
		"answer": "1000",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "The daily requirement of calcium is ___mg/day for 51+ yo",
        "answer": "1200",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "The UL for calcium for male/female is ____/_____/____mg/day for 9-19, 19-50, 51+",
		"answer": "3000, 2500, 2000",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Iron deficiency leads to",
		"choices": "weakness/pallor/cold digits/anemia, impaired exercise performance, decreased cognition and development in young children, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Iron deficiency needs to be watched in",
		"choices": "inadequate dietary intake, decreased vitamin C, periods of rapid growth or pregnancy, normal/drug induced or pathological blood loss incuding menstruation, all of the above, none of the above",
		"answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Iron excess leads to",
		"choices": "increased serum ferritin, GI/liver/vascular damage and shock due to free radical catalysis, constipation (dark, hard stools), all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the different forms of iron supplements: ferrous f_____, s_____, g____",
		"answer": "fumarate, sulfate, gluconate",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "R_____ iron is absorbed more readily than o____ iron",
        "answer": "reduced, oxidized",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "H_____ iron is absorbed more readily than i_____ iron",
		"answer": "heme, inorganic",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Plant sources of iron come from l______, fortified grain products, m______, s____",
        "answer": "legumes, molasses, spinach",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "The daily requirement",
		"answer": "1000",
        "type": "text"
    }
]